前情提要
U·N·欧文就是匿名
U·N·Owen is unknown.
我们必然有什么共同点
We must all have something in common.
有人认识我们所有人
Someone who knows us all.
是那首诗 就是那首诗 你们没发现吗?
It's the poem. It's the poem, don't you see?
不会有人来找我们的
No-one's coming for us. This is the end.
你喜欢雨果叔叔 对吧?
You like Uncle Hugo, don't you?
对 我爱上他了
I do. I am in love with him.
斧劈两半一命休 七个只剩六
One chopped himself in half and then there were six.
所以她说得对 和那首诗一样!
So she's right. It is the poem!
你和我都有犀利的头脑 我们应该待在一起
We have sharp minds. We should stay together.
房间是锁着的
It was locked.
所以一定有主钥匙
Which means there must be a master key.
钥匙可能在任何人手里
Any one of us could have had the key.
枪也可能在任何人手里
Any one of us could have the gun.
凶手不在外面
The killer is not out there.
凶手就在这
The killer is in here.
是我们中的一员
It is one of us.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
翻译: 凤梨酥
翻译: 無限月讀
翻译: 猫呗
校对: 影子
阿加莎·克里斯蒂作品
无人生还 第三集
看西里尔现在多开心啊
Look how happy Cyril is now.
雨果总是能让人意想不到
Hugo always works wonders.
他是我见过的最出色的年轻人了
He is the most marvellous man.
他看起来人很好
He seems very nice.
在那种情况下 我真的想不到能有人像他这么体贴
I really can't imagine many would be as kind, under the circumstances.
什么情况?
What circumstances?
我丈夫去世的时候 我并不知道我已经怀孕了
Well, I had no idea I was pregnant when my husband died.
所以 雨果作为我丈夫的侄子 应该是他的继承人
So Hugo, as the nephew, stood to inherit.
可是当西里尔出生之后 雨果就没希望了 唉!
And when little Cyril popped out, that was it for Hugo's hopes. Hm!
他应该娶一个有钱人家的女孩 可以继承父亲财产的那种
What he needs is some rich girl loaded down with Daddy's money,
不过他是个浪漫的人
but he's a romantic.
想为了爱情而结婚
Wants to marry for love.
可是没钱的话 他怎么结婚?
But how can he when he doesn't have a penny?
克莱索恩小姐 爱情可是一种非常昂贵的追求
Love, Miss Claythorne, is a very costly pursuit.
哦 西里尔 真棒! 哦!
Oh, well done, Cyril! Oh!
我也过去和他们一起玩
I might go and play with them.
嗨
Ah, hello.
看起来有人是想给我们奖励呢 西里尔
Looks like we've got some reinforcements, Cyril.
准备好了吗 小家伙?
Ready, old thing?
准备? 我可不觉得克莱索恩小姐能打到球
Ready? I don't think Miss Claythorne can hit a ball.
- 女孩们真的不行的 雨果叔叔  - 那我们试试看吧
- Girls can't, Uncle Hugo.  - Well, we'll have to see.
哦 打中了!
Oh, shot!
过来! 快点 快点!
Over here! Quick, quick!
快啊 她都要跑完一整圈了 快过来
Quick, she's going to get all the way around. Come on now.
真棒! 就差一点了
Well done! Almost.
我们不能就这么坐着什么都不干!
We can't just sit here doing nothing!
那我们应该怎样?
What are we supposed to do?
在岩石上生火求救?
Light a fire on the headland, signal for help?
这种天气可不行
Not in this weather.
她... 她要去哪里? 你要去哪?
Where's... where's she going? Where are you going?
去泡点茶 我一会就拿进来
To make tea. I'll bring it in.
你还要拿进来什么? 厨房里的刀?
What else are you going to bring in? A knife from the kitchen?
还是你藏起来的枪?
The gun from wherever you've hidden it?
你又要在茶里放什么?
And what are you going to be putting in the tea?
她会杀死我们所有人的!
She's going to wipe out all four of us!
我会在茶里放点柠檬
There'll be lemon in the tea.
我... 我不会拿刀进来 我也没有枪
I... I won't bring a knife and I don't have the gun.
就算我有 我也没法一下杀死你们所有人 不是吗?
Even if I did, I wouldn't be killing you all at the same time, would I?
- 我们凭什么信你?!  - 因为人是挨个死的 还有特定的死法
- How do we know that?!  - Because it's one by one and in a particular way,
你难道一点都没有注意到吗?
or have you not been paying attention?
那上面从来都没有提到过枪 对吗?
And nowhere on that does it say anything about a gun, does it,
你这个没有脑子的混蛋!
you idiotic, cretinous bastard?!
我和你一起去
I'll come with you.
不行!
No!
不行 我们... 要么一个人单独去 要么就大家一起去
No. We go... singularly, or in a group.
沃格雷夫法官 我听说你以前很喜欢判人绞刑
I hear you were one for the black square and the rope, Judge Wargrave.
有匹配的罪名的话 我确实很喜欢
When it was appropriate, yes.
这个胖子跟我说 你判死刑的罪犯行刑时 你都会去看
Tubs here tells me you used to watch all the hangings you'd ordered.
是真的吗?
Is that true?
真的 你别再这么叫我了
You really want to stop calling me that.
是真的吗 法官先生?
Is that true, Judge?
我有权因人们所犯的罪行而判他们死刑
I had the power to condemn men and women to death for their crimes.
权力越大 责任越大
With great power comes great responsibility.
我认为 如果在权力实行的时候 我却不在场的话
I believe that to look away as that power is exercised
就是不负责任和懦弱的表现
was both irresponsible and cowardly.
爱德华·塞顿受绞刑时 你在场吗?
Did you watch Edward Seton hang?
我还记得在报纸上看到过爱德华·塞顿的事
I remember Edward Seton, from the newspapers.
大家都说他是无辜的
Everyone said he was innocent.
他不是
He wasn't.
他留下了日记
He left diaries.
那上面记录了一个扭曲败坏的灵魂
They proved a warped and corrupted mind.
他认为他的受害者都是肮脏的
He believed his victims were full of filth
而他则是在清理这个世界的污浊
and that he was cleansing the world of their stain.
通过或正确或错误的线索嘲弄警察让他很开心
Taunting the police with... clues and misdirections excited him.
他就像虐待狂一样
As much as torture and sadism.
他有罪而你做出了正确的裁决
He was guilty and you passed the right verdict.
你为什么没有去观刑?
Why didn't you go and see him?
我去了
I did.
那一次场面很混乱
It was unsettling.
也与以往不同
Different.
他拒绝戴头罩
He refused the hood.
想让我看到他的脸
He wanted me to see his face.
可能是想证明我们之间有一些相似之处
Perhaps to impute there was some commonality between us,
也可能是... 想嘲讽我
perhaps to... laugh at me.
嘲讽你?
Laugh at you?
是的
Yes.
他想嘲讽正义
At justice.
因为这对他来说毫无意义
It meant nothing to him.
他不怕所谓的正义 也不怕我
He wasn't cowed by it, or by me.
我什么都不是
I was nothing.
很快就会被人们遗忘 成为历史的注脚
I would soon be forgotten, a footnote in history.
可是他却留下了恐怖和血腥
Whereas he, with his legacy of blood and horror,
并会被人永远记住
would be remembered for ever.
他还真的做到了
Well, it worked.
他至今仍然在我心头挥之不去
He haunts me still.
不过... 嘲笑与否
But... laughter or not,
正义总会到来
justice came, as it always does.
这个世界也不再被他的黑色恐怖所笼罩
And the world is free of his terrible darkness.
这样不行!
This is ridiculous!
我们不能就这么干坐着!
I mean, we can't just sit around doing nothing!
好啊 医生
Very well, Doctor.
我们说好要么单独 要么就一起行动
We said singly, or in a group.
我要去看会书了
I'm going to read.
阿姆斯特朗医生 我很抱歉 但是你这么激动真让我有点累了
I'm sorry, Dr Armstrong, but your agitation tires me greatly.
正义降临
Justice came.
杀手和沃格雷夫确实有着相似之处
The killer and Wargrave having common cause.
那就是造成他人死亡所带来的兴奋感
The same thrill... from handing out death.
我说起法官先生的时候你还嘲笑我来着
You took the piss when I said the judge.
是啊 不过现在我改变了看法
Yes, well, now I think different.
他看过多少个人被处以绞刑? 这对一个人会产生什么样的影响?
How many men has he seen dangle? What does that do to someone?
他现在正独自一人
He's on his own.
可以谋划任何事情
Could be plotting anything.
停下吧 行吗?! 别再弄出这种声音了!
Stop it, will you?! Just stop it!
说的就像我们没有忍你很久了似的
As if we haven't had to put up with you.
气喘吁吁 还抽烟
Breathing and smoking.
坐立不安 来回踱步
Scratching, fidgeting and pacing.
我要去休息了
I'm going to bed.
我自己去 或者谁来和我一起
Singly, or in a group.
你可以看着我上楼
You can watch me go up the stairs.
西里尔?!
Cyril?!
不!
No!
不要啊!
维拉?
Vera?
嘿
Hey!
维拉?
Vera?
给 天啊 就是碳酸铵而已 是一种嗅盐
Here. For Christ's sake, it's sal volatile. Smelling salts.
慢慢呼吸 从鼻子吸进去 从嘴里吐出来
Breathe slowly. In through the nose, out through the mouth.
这就对了
There we are.
我以为屋子里还有别人
I thought there was somebody in the room with me.
给 喝口白兰地吧
Here, have some brandy.
不错嘛 维拉
Good for you, Vera.
怎么了 你觉得我对这酒做了手脚?
What, you think I've done something to it?
我去拿一瓶没开过封的好了
I'm going to go and fetch another bottle that hasn't been opened.
- 我想喝水  - 这白兰地没问题的
- I need some water.  - This brandy's all right.
我什么都没干
I haven't done anything to it.
受到惊吓之后喝点白兰地酒挺好的 所以我才拿了过来
Brandy's good for shock, that's why I got it.
他叫她维拉
He called her Vera.
隆巴德 这是第二次了
Lombard. That's the second time.
他们俩之间肯定发生了什么
There's something going on between them.
密封的 没人动过的
Sealed and untampered with.
那是干什么用的?
What's that for?
我也不知道 可能是挂吊灯的吧
I don't know. A chandelier, maybe.
就像楼下那个一样
Like downstairs.
卧室里面挂吊灯?
A chandelier in the bedroom?
毕竟这里住的都是奢侈的人 不是吗?
Well, it's posh people, innit?
他们在任何地方都可能挂吊灯
They put a chandelier anywhere.
他们要是真有钱就应该在猪圈里也挂上吊灯
Put a chandelier in a pigsty if the fancy took them.
我都有点喜欢你了 胖子
I'm becoming very fond of you, Tubs.
你这个自大的混蛋
You're an arrogant arsehole, you.
哦! 该死! 我很抱歉 克莱索恩小姐
Ooh! Bloody hell! Sorry, Miss Claythorne.
没事 你说得对 他就是个混蛋!
No, you're right. He's an arsehole!
法官先生呢?
Where's the judge?
天啊!
Jesus!
他被人开枪打死了
He's been shot in the head.
你要干什么?
Well, what are you doing?
要是我们想挪动他的话 就得把他的头包起来
Well, his head needs to be wrapped if we're going to move him.
他说得对
He's right.
我们可不想他的脑子溅的地板上到处都是
We don't want his brains spilling out all over the floor.
别用你的外套 阿姆斯特朗 我找点别的东西
Don't use your jacket, Armstrong. I'll find something else.
枪杀?
Shot?
- 你确定吗?  - 你自己看啊!
- Are you sure?  - Well, look at him!
我们到处搜查那把枪
We searched everywhere for that gun.
你曾经下楼去拿瓶子
You went back downstairs to get the bottle.
你也曾经下楼去拿了杯白兰地
You went downstairs, too, to get a glass of brandy.
还有你 你也有段时间不见人影
And you, you disappeared for a bit.
那是为了取我的包以便照顾... 维拉!
To fetch my bag so that I could attend to... Vera!
我们没听见枪声
We didn't hear the shot.
你可能开枪的时候拿垫子捂住了
You could have muffled it with a cushion.
我们只能相信你说的了
Well, we'll have to take your word for it.
我从没对人的脑袋开过枪 你更擅长这个
I've never shot a man in the head. That's more your field of expertise.
我怎么可能有足够时间下楼
How would I have had the time to go downstairs,
拿瓶白兰地
grab a bottle of brandy,
在没人听见的情况下 飞快的对着沃格雷夫开一枪
quickly put a slug in Wargrave, making sure that nobody heard him,
还要给他穿好衣服再上楼来?
dress him up and make it back upstairs again?
这儿的胖子离开的时间更长
Tubs here was away for longer.
我可没你跑得快
I'm not as quick on my feet as you.
"五个士兵小男孩 惹是生非打官司
"Five little soldier boys going in for law
官司缠身直到死 五个只剩四"
One got Chancery and then there were four."
一个接一个被杀
One by one
按照诗里的方式
and in a particular way.
我的枪去哪儿了?
And where's my gun?
- 别瞪着我!  - 也别瞪着我!
- Don't bloody look at me!  - Or me!
我受不了那风声了
I can't stand the sound of that wind.
我受不了了!
I can't stand it!
我可不打算坐着等死!
I'm not just going to sit here and wait to die!
打仗时 经常这么干!
In the war, do this all the time!
避免打瞌睡!
And stay awake!
到处是尸体!
Bodies, bodies, bodies, bodies!
到处是骨骸 鲜血 残肢!
Bones, blood, skulls!
像这样恣意狂欢!
Just this... this... this... this parade!
充斥死亡的无尽狂欢!
Endless parade of shattered... shattered meats!
站在那儿 拆胳膊卸腿
Just standing there, cutting off legs and arms
尸骸遍布 惨叫连连!
and... guts everywhere and bodies and screaming!
女士们 先生们 请肃静!
Ladies and gentlemen, silence, please!
你们被指控犯有以下罪名...
You are charged with the following indictments...
爱德华·乔治·阿姆斯特朗...
Edward George Armstrong...
是我!
That's me!
威廉·亨利·布洛尔
William Henry Blore.
还有我!
Yeah, that's me!
你谋杀了詹姆斯·斯蒂芬·兰道
That you did murder James Steven Landor.
维拉·伊丽莎白·克莱索恩...
Vera Elizabeth Claythorne...
那种气味! 还有噪音 各种噪音!
The smell! And the noise, the noise, the noise...!
狱中的罪犯们 你们是否认罪?
Prisoners at the bar, how do you plead?
有罪!
Guilty!
你们在笑什么?
What are you laughing at?
布洛尔? 看看他们!
Blore? Watch them!
看看他们!
Watch them!
跟着我 维拉
You stick with me, Vera.
我们会挺过去的
We're going to get through this.
我可不打算被杀掉
I have no intention of getting killed.
其他人才会死 我们不会
Death... is for other people, not for us.
看到没? 看他们
You see? Look at them.
他们两个合谋 可能就是他们
Together. Perhaps it's them.
欧文夫妇
Mr and Mrs Owen.
是他们!
It's them!
好吧!
Fine!
我怎么带着这个傻帽子?!
Why am I wearing this fucking hat?!
我去睡了
I'm going to bed.
舞会结束了
This party's over.
看这里 帅哥 你被抓起来了
Now, look here, sunshine, you've been pinched.
我们都知道是为什么
And we know what for.
你躲在男厕所里鬼鬼祟祟
Lurking about in a gentleman's public convenience, in the bogs.
我是谁 又不是昨天才出生的?
What am I, born yesterday?
遇到我是你的运气
Now, you're lucky you got me.
亏得不是其他警察 他们可会下狠手
Not some other copper. He might've been a bit heavy-handed.
我说 看看你 你什么都不是!
I mean, look at you, there's nothing of you!
你软弱
You're soft.
像个桃子 或其他什么
Eh? Like a peach, or something.
一捏就碎
You'd be mush in a moment.
所以走吧
So go on.
走啊
On your way.
算是给你上了一课 行吗? 再小心些
Let this be a lesson to you, all right? Be more discreet.
你可不想鼻子流血
You don't want to end up getting a bloody nose
或是看不见的内伤什么的
or doing a stretch inside
因为号子里可不是好玩的
because it's no fun for you lot in the nick.
走啊 快跑
Go on, scarper.
谢谢
Thank you.
我本可以放你走的 对吧?
That's what I should've done, innit?
我本可以放你走
That's what I should've done.
但是我不会
But I didn't.
混蛋!
Bastard!
隆巴德! 隆巴德快出来!
Lombard! Lombard!
怎么了?
What is it?
是他 是阿姆斯特朗!
It's him. It is Armstrong!
他从房子里出去了 我看见他了
He's left the house, I saw him.
锁上门 维拉 用椅子抵住
Lock your door, Vera, and put a chair against it.
你还好吗?
How are you?
汉密尔顿太太怎么样了?
How is Mrs Hamilton?
我要带她去伦敦
I'm taking her to London.
她不能待在这里
She can't stay here.
当然了
Of course.
她愿意补偿你三个月的工资
She, um... wants to give you three months' pay in lieu of notice
既然没有孩子可教了
because, obviously, you cannot be a governess
你也不用再当女家教了
when there is no child to govern.
如果汉密尔顿太太去伦敦 我可以照看房子
If Mrs Hamilton is in London, I can look after the house.
即使我不做女家教了 我也可以照看房子
Even if I'm not governess, I can still look after the house.
以朋友的身份
As a friend.
我打算把房子锁起来
I'm locking the house up.
我猜房子会被卖掉
I imagine it might be sold.
可现在是你的房子了
But it's yours now.
我还是另寻住处吧
I will have to find somewhere to stay.
找个舒服的旅馆住下
I'll find a nice hotel.
等你来的时候
For when you come down.
也许我可以找个小屋子
Perhaps I'll find us a little cottage.
我得和奥利维亚待在一起
I have to be with Olivia.
她很不好
She's really rather unwell.
会有一场审讯
There will be an inquest.
他们打算快点办 所以会需要你
They want it to be quite soon, so you'll be needed.
没问题
Of course.
你会去吧?
And you'll come down for that?
我得走了
I have to go.
可怜的小西里尔
Poor little Cyril.
维拉? 是我们
Vera? It's us.
它就放在你床上
It was just on your bed.
它就放在我床上
It was just... on my bed.
我怎么知道昨晚你有没有把它放在那里?
Well, how do I know you didn't plant it in there last night?
如果菲利普在这之前就有枪 昨晚你们跟踪阿姆斯特朗的时候
If Philip had the gun before now, he would have taken it with you
他就该带上枪了 不是吗?
when you went after Armstrong, wouldn't he?
你可以偷偷溜出房间然后放在那里
You could have crept out of your room and planted it.
反正那时又没人盯着你
There was no-one around here to hear you.
我把门锁上了 以免阿姆斯特朗回来
I had my door locked in case Armstrong came back.
阿姆斯特朗消失了 凭空消失了
Armstrong's disappeared. Thin air.
昨晚我们分头找他了 不是吗?
We split up when we went searching last night, didn't we?
- 是的 我们分头找了  - 你找到了吗?
- Yes, we did.  - Did you find him?
你把他推下悬崖了吗?
Did you chuck him off the cliff?
不是的 胖子 我没有找到他
No, Tubs, I didn't find him
- 然后把他推下悬崖 你呢?  - 没有!
- and chuck him off the cliff. Did you? - No!
没有
No.
鱼
Red herring.
你说什么?
What?
"四个士兵小男孩 结伙出海遭大难
"Four little soldier boys going out to sea
鱼吞一个血斑斑 四个只剩三"
A red herring swallowed one and then there were three."
鱼
Red herring.
阿姆斯特朗还活着
Armstrong's still alive.
为什么每次都是你猜出来的?
Why's it always you that works it out?
从最开始起就这样 对吧?
Has been from the off, innit?
就是你猜出来的
Working it out.
阿姆斯特朗也那样说过
Armstrong said that and all.
这是个漫长的夜晚
It's been a long night.
酒精和毒品让你脑子糊涂了 胖子
You're letting the booze and powder do the thinking for you, Tubs.
我说过别那么叫我
I've told you to stop calling me that!
你的名字叫威廉 是吧?
Your first name's William, isn't it?
应该叫你威尔 还是...?
Do you get Will, or...?
比尔 叫我比尔
Bill. I get Bill.
好吧 比尔
Well, Bill,
大声放音乐
whose idea was it to put music on,
再喝个酩酊大醉 这样我们就听不见任何东西 这是谁的主意?
to get drunk so we'd all pass out and not hear anything?
- 阿姆斯特朗  - 你最开始怀疑的是谁?
- Armstrong.  - And who did you first suspect?
从最开始起 你觉得谁最可疑?
Who did you get the scent on, right from the off?
阿姆斯特朗
Armstrong.
鱼
Red herring.
从最开始起 他就在挑拨我们
He's been playing us off each other from the start.
而他现在还活着
And he's still alive.
因为像这么大的小岛上 人不会凭空消失
Because people don't just vanish, not on an island this size.
他还活着
He's still alive.
我家有一片农田
I've got an allotment at home.
在埃德蒙顿
In Edmonton.
我很喜欢
I love it.
那是我的乐土
It's my little patch of paradise.
那是世上最美的地方 单只坐在那里 看着一切
That's the best thing in the world, just sitting there, watching it all.
自在生长
Growing away.
嗯!
Hm!
从茶壶里倒杯茶 再来点面包和奶酪
Cup of tea from the flask and a bit of bread and a bit of cheese and...
还有刚刚从地里拔出来的萝卜
radish that you pulled from the ground a moment before.
又大又爽口的萝卜
Great, big, peppery radish.
很单纯
Simple things.
很幸福
Good things.
我后悔没把尤利克·诺尔曼·欧文的信直接扔进垃圾桶!
I wish I'd chucked that letter from Ulick Norman Owen in the bin!
可惜很对我口味
And it serves me right,
偷偷赚点外快
trying to earn... a bit of cash on the sly.
我们都喜欢如此
It serves us all right.
我们已经死了吗?
Are we dead already?
你说什么?
What?
也许我们已经死了 只是没有意识到而已
Perhaps we're dead already and we just don't realise it.
这就是地狱
And this is hell.
我们在地狱里
We're in hell.
我们为自己的罪行受到惩罚
And we're being punished for what we done.
因为我杀了他
Because I did kill him.
兰道
Landor.
我把他的脑浆都踩了出来
I stomped him till he was pulp.
踩得他妈都不认识他
His own mother couldn't see him.
道别都没能说一声
Couldn't say goodbye.
是我杀了他
I murdered him, all right.
他那么的无助 我没有停下
He was helpless and I didn't stop.
他一定很害怕
He must've been so frightened.
他只不过是个... 小伙子
Just... just a young lad.
我还有一地的番茄等着收割 谁来收割?
I've got a tomato crop that's got to be harvested. Who's going to do it?
我的田地会怎么样?
What's going to happen to my allotment?
嘿 嘿 得了 胖子
Hey. Hey, come on, Tubs.
咱们还没死呢
We're not done yet.
咱们三个对抗他一个 咱们能撑下去
It's us three against him. We can hold our own.
而且一定有人来救我们 一定... 会的
And someone has to come for us soon. They... they have to.
对 说得对
That's the spirit.
谁会来救我们呢?
Who's going to come for us?
那个该出现的纳拉科特从来没有出现过
That Narracott never turned up when he was supposed to.
估计他被买通了
Reckon he was paid off.
我们去生火
We light a fire.
在崖边生火 一定会有人看到的
On the cliff. Someone's bound to see it.
那就需要补给
OK. We're going to need supplies.
我不想再在这里过夜了 你们呢?
I don't want to spend another night in this house, do you?
估计我们被人监视了
I reckon we're being watched.
的确
We are.
- 走吧  - 好的
- Let's go.  - OK.
快点 胖子 我们走!
Come on, Tubs, let's go!
他在哪?!
Where is he?!
待在这别走
Stay here.
别跟着我!
Don't follow me!
三个士兵小男孩 动物园里遭祸殃
Three little soldier boys walking in the zoo
狗熊突然从天降 三个只剩两
A big bear hugged one and then there were two.
可怜的胖子
Poor Tubs.
涨潮了!
The tide's changing!
菲利普?
Philip?
菲利普!
Philip!
下面有什么东西
There's something down there.
阿姆斯特朗
Armstrong.
- 走吧!  -去哪?
- Come on!  - Where?
反正不是这儿
Not here.
我们得找个视角更好的地方
I need to find a better view.
不 不 不 我们... 我们不能把他留在这里
No, no, no. We... we can't leave him like this.
不可以这样 我们不能留下他
It's not right. We can't leave him!
可以留下他
Yes, we can.
不 等船来了 菲利普 他们会看到他的
No, when the boat comes, Philip, they'll see him like this
我们还没有摆脱嫌疑 做... 该做的事
and we haven't done the decent, the... the right thing.
他们会怎么看我们?
How will it look for us?
拜托了!
Please!
是你!
It's you!
是你! 全是你干的 你干的!
It's you! It's all you, all of it!
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
你会杀了我的!
You're going to kill me!
不! 不 我不会杀你的 维拉
No! No, I'm not going to kill you, Vera.
- 但是岛上还有别人...  - 岛上没有别人了!
- But there's somebody else on this island...  - No, there's no-one else!
你不把枪给我 那个人会把我们俩都杀掉
There's somebody on this island and they're going to kill us both if you don't give me that gun.
没有别人了 你把他们都杀了!
There's no-one else, you've killed them all!
听我说 我们被猎捕了!
Listen to me, we're being hunted!
现在 我们都被猎捕了!
Right now, we're being hunted!
我需要那把枪!
I need the gun!
把枪给我
Give it to me.
维拉?
Vera?
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
把枪给我 维拉
Give me the gun, Vera.
我答应他下课后可以玩棒球
I promised him a game of bat and ball after our lessons.
表现好的奖励
A reward for being so good.
他想游泳
He wanted to swim.
他总是想游泳
He always wanted to swim.
但是我不同意
But I said no.
我去拿棒球棒和棒球的时候...
I went to get the bat and ball for our game...
他就跑了
and he was gone.
我跑去追他
I ran after him.
用尽全力地跑
I ran as fast as I could.
要是我没有回头就好了
If only I hadn't turned away for a minute,
但是我去拿棒球 就那么短短的一分钟
but it was only a minute while I got the bat and ball.
要是...
If only...
谢谢你 谢谢你去救他
Thank you. Thank you for trying to save him.
天啊! 天啊!
Oh, God! Oh, God!
之前 我还不确定
You know, before, I wasn't sure.
但是现在我确定了
But I am sure now.
看着你 听着你的供词
Watching you, hearing you speak.
现在我确定了
Now I'm sure.
- 确定什么了?  - 你在说谎
- What are you sure of?  - That you're lying.
你连西里尔都... 追不上?
You couldn't catch up with... Cyril?
我看过你跑步 维拉
I've seen you run, Vera.
你很强壮 你跑得那么快 百米冲刺
You're fast. You're strong. You sprint.
只是回头走了几步路 你就追不上西里尔了?
You turn your back for a moment and you couldn't catch up with Cyril?
- 雨果 你不能这么想...  - 我知道你为什么要这么做
- Hugo, you can't think this...  - I know why you did it.
但是你根本不知道我有多爱那个孩子
But what you don't understand is that I really loved that little boy.
我也爱他 我还爱你
So did I. And I love you.
我没法证明 我证明不了
I can't prove it. I can't prove a thing.
但是 维拉 假如我有证据... 我很想看着你上绞架
Oh, but, Vera, if I did have proof... I'd see you hang.
西里尔?
Cyril?
听着...
Now...
你有本事游到那块岩石吧?
you're strong enough to swim to that rock, aren't you?
你足够强壮了 激动吗?
You're strong enough. Excited?
好了 准备好 去吧!
OK. On your marks, get set, go!
马上到了!
Nearly there!
坚持住!
Hold on!
别害怕 我来救你了 我来救你了
Don't worry. I've got you. I've got you.
是雨果吗?
Hugo?
两个士兵小男孩 太阳底下长叹息...
Two little soldier boys sitting in the sun...
晒死烤死悲戚戚 两个只剩一
One got frizzled up and then there was one.
一个士兵小男孩 归去来兮只一人...
One little soldier boy left all alone...
悬梁自尽了此生 一个也不剩
He went and hanged himself and then there were none.
你是不是很好奇脑浆是哪来的...?
You wondering about that...?
那是猪肝和腰子
Liver and kidneys.
医生说我死了 你们都相信了
You all believed the doctor when he said I was dead.
- 没人检查  - 让我下来!
- None of you checked.  - I need to get down!
阿姆斯特朗把事情简化了太多
Armstrong made it so much easier.
他很热衷于联盟
He was very keen to forge an alliance.
我不知道他以为会发生什么事
I don't know what he thought was going to happen
夜里他跑到外面来找我
when he ran out into the night to meet me.
大概以为我会救他
Perhaps that I was going to save him.
关于手术的事 我说谎了
I lied about the success of my surgery.
癌症肿瘤在扩散
The mass, the tumour is spreading.
除了等死 我无事可做
There's nothing to be done but await the inevitable.
而且病痛折磨着我
It's quite extraordinarily painful.
但是... 疼不了多久了
Well... not long now, though, hm?
你为什么这么做?
Why are you doing this?
因为人人必得公正
Because justice comes to all.
我和你们说过 你没听吗?
I told you that, were you not listening?
让我宣判爱德华·塞顿有罪的证据
The evidence that led me to convict Edward Seton
过于可怕 不宜公开
was considered too terrible to be made public.
犹如噩梦
It was the stuff of nightmares.
的确
Really.
而其他人被杀的时候...
And where others were revolted...
克莱索恩小姐 那让我着迷
Miss Claythorne, I was fascinated.
当塞顿直视我的双眼时
And when Seton looked into my eyes,
他可以看出我内心的兴奋
he could see that I was thrilled.
他知道我俩志趣相投
He knew that I was a kindred spirit.
而当他的脖子折断时...
And when his neck snapped...
我感到仿佛收到了一个礼物
I felt as if I'd been handed a gift.
不 不!
No. No!
你不是故意的
You don't mean any of this.
你是个好人 道德高尚
You are a good man. Moral.
道德高尚?
Moral?
也许确实高尚
Maybe there's something in that.
塞顿和我有些不一样
There are differences between Seton and myself.
他的受害者都是无辜的
All his victims were innocent.
你们都是有罪的
You are all guilty.
想象一下
Now, imagine.
探长们走进来 看到一屋子被屠杀的尸体
The detectives arrive to find a house full of slaughter
U·N·欧文的杰作到处都是
and the handiwork of UN Owen everywhere.
但是U·N·欧文本人却不见踪迹
But UN Owen himself is nowhere to be seen.
但是杀掉清白无辜的法官的最后一枪
But who else could have fired the final shot
由谁来扣动扳机呢?
that ended the life of the unimpeachable judge?
十具尸体 不见杀手
Ten bodies and no murderer.
此人如何消失无踪?
How could he have disappeared?
真是高深莫测
It's so unfathomable.
他们会调查个好几年
They'll be worrying about it for years.
不! 不 等等!
No! No, wait!
没有... 没有... 没有子弹了!
There's... there's no... there's no more bullets!
没人... 没人可以扣动扳机
There... there can be no final shot
因为弹夹是空的
because the gun is empty.
没有子弹剩下了
There are no more bullets.
该死!
Damn!
全浪费了
That's all spoiled.
不 没有浪费
No, it's not spoiled.
对啊 周围都是尸体 就剩我一个人
Yes, it is. There are corpses everywhere and only me left.
不 不光有你 还有我!
No, not just you. There's me!
剩下了我们两个
The two of us, together.
我们可以... 可以说是菲利普干的
We'll... we'll say it was Philip.
他发疯了
That he was mad.
我觉得他是我们当中最清醒的一个
Oh, he was quite the sanest of the lot, I thought.
他发疯了
He was insane.
他... 杀了我们所有人 我杀了他
He... he killed us all and I shot him.
我杀了他以自卫
I shot him to defend us.
全是菲利普·隆巴德干的
It was all Philip Lombard.
他是你的情人
You took him as your lover.
是的
Yes.
- 你的脚上有他的血  - 自我防卫!
- Got his blood on your feet.  - Self-defence!
我们就这么说
We'll say that.
我们就这么说 他们会相信我们的
We'll say that. They'll believe us.
上次他们就相信了我
They believed me last time.
你真是个满嘴谎言的女人 克莱索恩小姐
What a beguiling woman you are, Miss Claythorne.
维拉
Vera.
其实我挺喜欢的
Quite my favourite, really.
没有最后一颗子弹了 法官
There's no final bullet, Judge.
但是我可以让我们俩活下来
But I can save us both.
我会保守秘密 让我们俩活下来
I'll keep your secret and I'll save us both.
求你 放我下来!
Just let me down. Please!
你忘记"杀死"我的那颗子弹了
You forgot the one that shot me.